[
    {
        "question": "The original name of New York City was what?",
        "answer": "New Amsterdam"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hawaii`s tallest mountain is on which island?",
        "answer": "Hawai`i"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is the Panama Canal?",
        "answer": "51 miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s longest highway?",
        "answer": "Pan-American Highway"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state is known for its Juicy Lucy burgers?",
        "answer": "Minnesota"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where were the world`s largest pearls found?",
        "answer": "The Philippines"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country pioneered the concept of `Gross National Happiness`?",
        "answer": "Bhutan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S. state is home to a town called `Why`?",
        "answer": "Arizona -- The name comes from a former Y-shaped intersection of two nearby highways. The intersection design has since changed."
    },
    {
        "question": "The most self-reported ancestry in the U.S. is from what country?",
        "answer": "Germany -- German-American is the largest self-reported ancestry according to the U.S. Census Bureau."
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country can you find Hallerbos also known as the `Blue Forest`?",
        "answer": "Belgium -- Tens of millions of bluebells carpet the 1360-acre forest floor in a stunning periwinkle color each spring."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country calls itself Magyarorsz\u00e1g, meaning `Land of the Magyars`?",
        "answer": "Hungary -- The Magyars were semi-nomadic people who started occupying the basin of the Danube River in the 9th century."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has the most airports?",
        "answer": "USA -- There are more than 13,000 in the U.S. \u2014 more than 3 times the number in Brazil, the next on the list."
    },
    {
        "question": "Notre Dame Cathedral was built in what architectural style?",
        "answer": "Gothic -- Looming over \u00cele de la Cit\u00e9 in Paris, it is inarguably the most well-known Medieval Gothic cathedral in the world."
    },
    {
        "question": "What natural `Wonder of the World` lies off the east coast of Australia?",
        "answer": "The Great Barrier Reef"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US territory`s official motto is `Where America`s Day Begins`?",
        "answer": "Guam"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the four southernmost states that border Nebraska?",
        "answer": "Missouri, Iowa, Kansas and Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Pacific Ocean trench is the deepest in the world?",
        "answer": "Mariana trench"
    },
    {
        "question": "What area on the tip of South America has a name which translates as `Land of Fire`?",
        "answer": "Tierra del Fuego"
    },
    {
        "question": "On what continent would you find the Great Victoria Desert?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country does the island of Curacao belong to?",
        "answer": "The Netherlands"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did bungee jumping originate?",
        "answer": "Vanuatu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which major European city has zero stop signs?",
        "answer": "Paris"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is famously shaped like an elephant`s head?",
        "answer": "Thailand"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country`s land is mostly on an island, although most of its people live on a peninsula across the South China Sea?",
        "answer": "Malaysia"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to its former minister of tourism, which country is known abroad for its three Rs: reggae, romance and running?",
        "answer": "Jamaica"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mauritius is the only African country where the most commonly practised religion is what?",
        "answer": "Hinduism"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did Thomas Jefferson purchase the territory of Louisiana?",
        "answer": "1803"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mogadishu is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Somalia"
    },
    {
        "question": "The United States shares a land border with how many countries?",
        "answer": "Two"
    },
    {
        "question": "What South American city`s citizens are known as `Cariocas`?",
        "answer": "Rio de Janiero"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Great Lake was known by the Ojibway as `great water`?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What U.S. President`s family home was known as the `Sherwood Forest Plantation`?",
        "answer": "John Tyler"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Spanish word refers to a deep gully and precedes `Grande` in the name of a village in Southern California?",
        "answer": "Arroyo"
    },
    {
        "question": "As of 2020, which European country got about 3/4 of its electricity from nuclear power, the most of any country?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of India",
        "answer": "New Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state owns most of the Aleutian Islands?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Mormon founded Salt Lake City?",
        "answer": "Brigham Young"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Mead is a US reservoir created by what dam?",
        "answer": "Hoover Dam"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Green Mountain State`?",
        "answer": "Vermont"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Southern Hemisphere, summer begins in what month?",
        "answer": "December"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bucharest is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Romania"
    },
    {
        "question": "By area, what is the smallest of the Great Lakes?",
        "answer": "Lake Ontario"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is Japan closer to the North Pole or the South Pole?",
        "answer": "North Pole"
    },
    {
        "question": "The geothermal spa `Blue Lagoon` is located in what country?",
        "answer": "Iceland"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country is the San Andreas Fault located?",
        "answer": "United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the world`s smallest country?",
        "answer": "Vatican City state"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which continent would you find gauchos?",
        "answer": "South America"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the longest river in the US?",
        "answer": "Missouri"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only major city located on two continents?",
        "answer": "Istanbul"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many McDonald`s are in the country of Iceland?",
        "answer": "None"
    }
]